It's true. I've got a 12 core 3900X at home, and honestly, I don't use all those cores most of the time.
If I didn't dabble with running multiple virtual machines, I'd be just as well off with an 8 core or even a 6 core CPU,
especially if all I wanted to do was game.
In fact, 6 cores is what I went with for my VR rig.
Sure, there's stuff like compiling code and non-GPU rendering,
but the reality is that anybody serious enough about coding or graphics to be looking at a Threadripper
would probably also be looking at a separate build or render box so their workstation isn't unusable while the job's being done.
If, say, I ran a Plex instance, a personal web server, and maybe mess around with a Windows or Mac OS virtual machine,
that'd be roughly half my dozen cores, and I'd probably be more pressured on memory and storage at that point.
Now, would I complain if I had 16 cores to play with?
No.
But I don't need them either. I don't even need what I have now.
By the time I do, pricing for those extra cores, not to mention platform features like PCI Express Gen 5 and DDR5,
will come down and it'll all be more mature to boot.
The only times I've personally gone for, like, the top-end consumer processors
were the Core i7-3770K I got with Intel Retail Edge on the cheap,
and the Core i7-6700K near the tail end of the quad-core-is-all-you-need years,
so I'd have the extra threads to work with.
And that's just me comparing my 12 cores to 16, let alone Threadripper with up to 64.
Now, you could argue that Threadripper would stay relevant for way longer than any desktop chip would,
but you'd be wrong about that.
The 16-core Threadripper 1950X workstation that I use to type this script is slow as balls,
and I have never once used all the cores.
I desperately want more IPC and faster memory.
I'd happily trade for a 5800X or even a 5600X and some fast memory.
I'm not even using more PCI Express lanes than a modern Ryzen desktop can handle.
And I'm Anthony!